now that we have seen how the arob based
processor works when we have reservation
stations for separate units separately
let's talk about unified reservation
stations so this is what we had so far
we had three reservation stations for
the ad unit and we had two for the
multiply unit this also does subtracts
this also does divides and we have seen
it in at least one of our examples that
we can run out of these reservation
stations while we still have plenty of
these left however we still could don't
issue instructions basically once we
cannot issue an instruction because it
needs one of these reservation stations
because issue needs to happen in order
we cannot issue any of these either so
until these reservation stations become
available we cannot really use the
available ones here note that these
reservation stations are exactly the
same except that this one is feeding
this unit and this one is feeding this
unit but the logic in them is exactly
the same they're monitoring all of the
results that are broadcast capturing
results and then going to execution
units so to improve Arab ability to use
the expensive reservation stations we
can go with the so-called unified
reservation stations approach where all
of the reservation stations are in one
big array now when we need to issue we
need to grab one of these reservation
stations but it doesn't matter which
unit it is for basically all of the
reservation stations are equal so the
benefit of this is that as long as there
are any available reservation stations
we can issue instructions the drawback
here is that the logic for dispatching
instructions into these execution units
becomes a little bit more
complicated here for issue into the
multiplication we only needed to see
whether one of these is available and If
one or more are available select one
meanwhile here we're selecting one of
these three and sending it to the ad
unit and if more than one are available
we have to figure out just which one of
the three here however every cycle we
need to select one of these for the add
and one of these for the multiply so we
need to actually consider which one of
these are ads to go here which one of
these are multiplies to go here and then
every cycle we need to select one of the
ads and one of the multiplies to go
there so the logic for dispatching
becomes more complicated here because we
have more reservation stations to look
at and we also for each unit need to
look at reservation stations that just
have wrong things for that unit so we
have to ignore them but again
reservation stations are very very
expensive so usually processors will use
some variant of this organization rather
than this one basically we don't have
each unit having its own reservation
stations typically a group of units will
have a reservation station so that we
can benefit from our reservation
stations if we have them